When I went and bid my first deal, I told
the guy we would do a billion dollars in 10 years.
We hadn't sold the policy. A billion.
We just finished our 10th
year. We didn't do a billion.
We're just shy of $800 million, which was so obnoxious.
But that was my goal.
And I say to him all
the time, do you believe me?
He's like, dude, I didn't think you'd do $50 million.
Nobody does $50 million, let alone $750 million.
In my 20s, if I had made a million
dollars a year, you know what I'd have done?
Killed myself, probably.
I like smoking crack. I like
using cocaine. I've been sober 23 years.
I like to drink too much.
If I made a million dollars when I was
22, I wouldn't be talking to you right now.
I'd be in prison or dead.
What's been your secret to sales?
You know why most people struggle with sales?
Do you know why most people struggle with sales?
If I asked you why, what do you think?
Why do you think most people struggle with sales?
I don't think they believe in themselves.
That's a good answer, because that's part of it.
And then that lack of belief
causes them not to work hard.
I always tell people, when I
started making money, my friends were like,
yo, you think you're better
than us, behind my back, obviously.
And I'd be like, I
don't think I'm better than you.
I just want more out of life than you.
How can somebody own a private jet?
What's going on, Hard Knocks family?
And welcome back to Questions with Multi-Millionaires.
I'm James, and I've got
a very special guest here today.
I'm here with Sean Mike.
How you doing, man?
Doing great.
We are out on his private jet in Miami, Florida.
And for those who don't know Sean, could you
give us a little bit of a background on yourself
and how you got to where you are now?
Yeah, man.
I was born and raised in
Connecticut, and I was broke as shit.
And I didn't want to live my life broke.
I went to college to play ball.
That was about it.
Got done playing ball.
Had a job for the state.
And after a while, I
decided to get into real estate.
And I built companies from there.
I never got in business to be rich,
but it's obviously done very well for me.
I've become wealthy, which has been amazing.
So real estate, waste management, life insurance.
Do a lot of investments at a lot of
different companies that I run or I'm on the board.
And had a lot of successful exits, and
I've just learned a lot along the way.
And I love what you're doing because
you're trying to give back to people.
You're trying to truly educate people and give them the
courage to go out there and figure out the information
that a lot of people won't share with them.
People will share if you ask them.
And I love that you're asking me, man.
So I live in Florida now.
It's much nicer down here.
And I live in Boca Raton.
So if you stay in this jet long enough,
we're going to go from here back to my house.
So you'll be stuck.
I love it.
So let me ask you this.
You kind of doubled down, become
an expert in the insurance business.
Do you think entrepreneurs starting out, should they focus and
become an expert, get really good at that one thing?
Or what are your thoughts on diversification for
entrepreneurs as opposed to just sticking to one industry?
That's a great question, by the way.
First of all, you ain't going to be an expert.
You know what I mean?
I'm really good at life insurance.
I do more distribution than
anybody in my market by far.
I'm not an expert.
I'm getting better at it every single
day, and I'm learning every single day.
I think that you need to
figure out what's making you money.
The problem with most entrepreneurs, they do nine things.
And I go, okay, which
one of them makes you money?
And then when they tell me,
I go, show me on paper.
Oh, really?
Like some of the people you interview, they
should show you if they're making money for real.
All I got to do
is put you on a jet.
But they should show you if they're making money, honestly.
Because most people go, I'm doing all these things.
I go, cool, give me your P&L.
Show me what you're making.
What's your net?
Like what is your EBITDA?
Are you making money?
So if you're doing nine things
and one of them makes you money,
I wouldn't necessarily try to be an expert.
I just spend all my time doing
the one thing that made me money.
Then when I started making real good money,
I could go ahead and explore other things.
But diversity kills most people in business
because they're spread so thin that they're like,
I'm in nine things.
I'm so diverse.
Look at my portfolio.
I'm like, none of it makes you any money.
So the key is what's making you money.
And also, the thing that makes you money
may not be the thing you love right now.
That's okay.
Go make it a bunch of
money and then pursue what you love.
So where do you find
that balance of following your passion
as opposed to following what you're good at?
Depends on what you want in life, right?
Like how old are you?
You got any kids?
No.
You can follow whatever the hell you want.
Seriously.
Right now, you can follow whatever you want until you
decide to get to where you need to get to.
But if you were 33 with two
kids, I'd be like, you can't do that.
You have to go make money.
So the reality really is nobody can
tell you what you need to do.
And that's the problem for most people
is like they want everybody else's advice.
Okay, well, for a minute, take your own advice.
Just for a minute, figure
out what do you really want.
So I think, you know, for me, I did a
lot of things I didn't love doing to make money
to then go do things I love
doing and love doing to make money.
But it took some time.
And the biggest struggle in today's world right now
is every 20, 22, 25-year-old wants to be rich.
I didn't make a million dollars a
year until I was in my 40s.
I wasn't making.
But it's a grind.
Now, there are things you can do to expedite.
If I knew then what I know now, yes, I
would have made a million dollars a year in my 20s.
But that was never my goal.
I never sought out to make money.
I was a social worker
working with abused and neglected children.
For $58,000 a year.
And I loved my job, dude.
Like, I loved it.
But then I got to a point where I'm
like, I want to provide more for my kids.
I want to do more with the community.
I want to give back.
So the balance is you have
to decide what the balance is.
Some people, money doesn't matter to them at all.
And when people hate on them, that's like, I had a
guy say, if you don't make a certain amount of money,
then you're this and that and the other thing.
I'm like, well, first of all, would you
say that to my face or somebody else's face?
Because when I was making 80 grand a year, that bitch
that said that, I'd still knock his teeth down his throat.
And he'd be spitting them out like bloody chickens.
Seriously, he'd choke on them.
So I'd kick his ass when
I was making 60 grand a year.
I'd kick his ass now.
Don't talk about people like that.
So you figure out what you want to do, man.
If you love what you're doing and you're making
enough money to get by, who cares what people think?
It shouldn't matter to you.
That's the problem, dude.
What does it matter?
It doesn't matter.
And you brought up how you didn't start making a
million dollars a year until you were in your 40s.
Correct.
Everybody, they want it overnight.
They want to get rich quick.
How important was it to have that delayed
gratification for you as opposed to, you know,
wanting it instantaneously like
everybody else in today's world?
I was building businesses.
I was building equity in my businesses.
And I sold those businesses for,
I mean, in excess of $100 million.
Like, life's really good, right?
But for me, I wasn't trying
to make a certain amount of money.
I was trying to build
real leverage, real equity, real wealth.
So I was, and honestly, I thought to myself, in
my 20s, if I had made a million dollars a year,
you know what I'd have done?
Killed myself probably.
I liked smoking crack.
I liked using cocaine.
I've been sober 23 years.
I liked to drink too much.
If I made a million dollars when I was
22, I wouldn't be talking to you right now.
I'd be in prison.
I'd be in jail.
And I'm not trying to be funny.
Like, what would I have done with it?
And people always say to me, well, if I had this
amount of money, I would do this with it for my business.
I go, you don't even know
what to do with it yet.
So, number one, if you can go make a
million dollars a year and you're 18, good for you.
But at the end of the day, if
you think that everybody you see on social media,
dude, I've had people take videos of this
plane that I own and say it's theirs.
I'll scroll on the Instagram.
I'm like, dude, that's weird.
That's my plane.
And he'll be like, got my jet.
And I'm like, motherfucker, that's my jet.
Like, why?
But that's how people are.
And, again, perception becomes reality.
So, it is a grind.
Now, let's say you create something.
Let's say you're super freaking smart, super creative,
and you create an app and it explodes.
Good for you.
But you're a very small percentage of the population.
The majority of us have to get good
at sales, service business, do something that's customer-centric,
and understand how to scale it.
And that's what I learned how to do.
I was like, let me find service businesses.
And, again, I could have made
a million dollars in my 30s.
I could have paid myself.
I could have paid myself more for my companies.
Without a doubt.
But I'm like, it came in.
I went back in the business.
It came in.
I funded the hell out of my businesses.
My businesses were eating.
Thus, they were growing.
And my competitors, they were just
taking all their money and spending it.
And I'm like, dude, I got a Honda Accord.
But I got tens of millions
of dollars in equity over here.
Then I have this over here.
Delayed gratification was easy for me
because I was raised with no money.
Like, none.
So, when I started making any kind of
money, I was like, damn, this is wacky.
Like, I have a house.
I didn't live in a house.
Right.
Like, nobody had a house.
We lived in apartments.
A lot of them were subsidized apartments,
like, based on your income kind of deal.
So, for me, man, I think it's a grind.
And please don't get frustrated when you don't do
it in a year or two years or three years.
And just because somebody drives a nice car don't mean
that they have any real net worth in any capacity.
So, let me ask you this.
A big component of a lot of
the businesses that you've been in is sales.
Real estate, insurance, sales is crucial.
A lot of people struggle with sales in today's world.
But what's been your secret to sales?
You consistently land massive deals with
huge clients over all these years.
What's your secret to selling in a competitive industry?
You know why most people struggle with sales?
Do you know why most people struggle with sales?
If I asked you why, what do you think?
Why do you think most people struggle with sales?
I don't think they believe in themselves.
That's, hey, that's a good
answer because that's part of it.
And then that lack of belief
causes them not to work hard.
The biggest thing I want to
sell people is belief in themselves.
I've gotten really, I believe in myself.
You give me a product, if people need it,
and I believe in it, I will sell it.
I don't give a shit what it is.
It doesn't matter.
If you go, sell these shoes,
I'd be like, are they good shoes?
Damn, I'll sell them.
Sell the shirt.
I'll sell that shirt off of your back to him.
It's no problem because I believe in me
as long as there's a potential customer, right?
But people don't want to work hard.
And what's the biggest cause of a
low self-image and a lack of self-belief?
Lack of unconditional love.
If you take people that grew
up with nobody giving them unconditional love,
people loved them conditionally.
So when you become good at
business, people will love you conditionally.
The Detroit Lions just lost last night, and they're
going to kill that coach for a whole year.
Everything they did during the season, they loved him.
But now what he's learning
is that was conditional love, bro.
Provide for us.
We love you.
You lose.
We hate you.
And that's how fast people turn.
But it's lack of belief in themselves.
But you can build the belief in yourself.
The greatest thing for your self-image by far is work.
That's the greatest thing.
So weirdly enough, I became really good
at sales because I called more people.
I wasn't going to take no for an answer.
I wasn't worried about being judged.
I breathed life into people.
I knew how to make relations with people.
I knew psychology.
I knew how to make relationships with people.
Like right now, you're thinking about what I'm thinking.
I'm thinking about what you're thinking.
That's the way that it works.
Now, you're a thinker, which is good.
So it's more challenging for me.
But you're not that hard to
read because it's who you are.
It's what you exude.
I understood the psychology of people.
And also, I didn't think it was
that competitive because most people won't work.
See, my deal is I didn't bring
anything to the table but my work ethic.
And I'll tell you what.
The deals I've gotten, like some of these
big distribution deals, I've sold my work ethic.
When we launched a life insurance deal, the guy said to me,
I was trying to get an insurance company to work with me.
One.
Anybody.
Dude flew in from Texas.
I'd done some research on him.
His dad was a high school football coach.
Very successful.
And we started talking.
And he gave me the 27
reasons why he shouldn't work with me.
No experience.
Don't have the capital to back it up.
All of these other things.
And I was working with somebody else.
And then when you work at a company, you
get good and you leave, they want to sue you.
I've been sued tons of
times and I could care less.
I had to sue people back.
It didn't matter to me at all.
But I said to him, I looked at him and I
said, what I have to sell you is my work ethic.
And I will outwork myself.
Mother freaking everybody.
And that's the beauty of it.
And the reason I've been good at creating good
sales people is a lot of people you'll talk to,
a lot of people I talk to that are
good at anything, they'll tell you how good they are.
Dude, if you can be a mirror instead
of a window, somebody says something good about you,
put it on to somebody else.
And that's how I've always been.
And I want people to say, when I built sales
organizations, I go to all the top people and I go,
hey, James, can anybody do what you're doing?
Hey, Derek.
Hey, Andrew.
Can anybody do what you're doing?
And if they go, no.
And they start talking.
How they're special.
I don't let them train.
I don't let them talk to anybody.
Because their ego will get everybody else
to go, like, that's why they're good.
Oh, I get it.
That's why they're good.
Like, athletics takes talent.
Like, when I can throw a
baseball, I've been hard for you.
I can throw a baseball.
Like, I was good at it.
I could tackle.
But then to play at another
level, you have to have certain.
You don't have to have a skill set in business.
Business literally doesn't discriminate.
You don't have to have any skill set.
You're a good salesperson.
So anybody can be a good salesperson.
But most people are terrified of what people.
We're going to think about them.
And back to what you said, which is,
you're right, is lack of belief in themselves.
How do they create people said me?
Well, how do I help my self-image?
I'm like, I have a great
book for you to read about it.
You got a pen?
Write the title.
You got a phone?
They're like, yeah.
I'm like, you got the title?
It's W-O-R-K.
Go to work.
And the more you work and the more you grind
and the more you go through stuff, the better you become.
And then your self-image grows.
And for me, I want people to grow their self-image.
I want people to be interviewed.
If it's what you want, I
want them interviewing you one day.
And not in the very, like in the
near future, like, dude, how did you do this?
Then I want you to tell them everything you
did and not keep any of it to yourself.
That's the magic, dude.
That's why I've been really good at sales.
Beautiful answer.
We're about to get right
back to the interview with Sean.
But I've got a question for you guys.
Are you enjoying this interview that
I'm doing with Sean right now?
Well, if you are, you will have the ability to hop on a live call I'm hosting with Sean
this Wednesday at 7 o'clock Eastern time inside of the private community we just launched called the School of Mentors.
And inside of our private entrepreneur community.
I'm hosting live.
I've calls every single week
with the millionaires and the billionaires.
You see us interview on this channel.
You'll be able to ask them questions
about your career, your life and your business.
You're also going to get access to exclusive networking
with like-minded people as well as exclusive content and masterclasses.
I've been filming with the most
successful entrepreneurs in the entire world.
You do not want to miss out on the opportunity to join the School of
Mentors because it is currently $30 a month for the first 1,000 members that join.
But it's filling up very fast.
So be one of the first to join.
And I can't wait to see you
on the inside of the School of Mentors.
With that being said.
Let's get back to the interview.
I wanted to ask you like what's the significance and the importance of being
able to sell yourself in business as opposed to just having great products and services?
Because you take a guy like Elon Musk.
He can walk into any company
and land a $50 billion deal.
So how important for you has it been being able to sell yourself
in business beyond just the great products and services you may have to offer?
Let's take, I mean listen.
It's Elon Musk, right?
But the dude figured out what he's great at.
And I don't know him.
So I don't hear him talk a lot.
But I've never heard him
talk about stuff he doesn't know.
Like stay in your lane.
So for me, I've always.
Because that's something.
That's such a great question.
I've always sold what I'm good at.
And a lot of people sell themselves.
And dude, there's nobody's good at everything.
And there's also a lot of brilliance
in telling people what you can't do.
Because that's humility.
So when I'm selling myself, I want to
sell how confident I am because I am.
But I'm also selling you on
the fact that I have humility.
Because you can't have a
big business and a big ego.
You know this guy did.
Well, if he built a product.
But it's hard to create distribution.
Get people to follow you.
Do something that's duplicatable.
If you think.
You're better than everybody.
I always tell people.
When I started making money.
My friends are like.
Yo, you think you're better than us.
Behind my back obviously.
And I'd be like.
I don't think I'm better than you.
I just want more in life than you.
I'm not any better than you.
You could.
Hey, sadly enough.
You could do exactly what I'm doing.
You choose not to.
I'm not mad at you, bro.
Don't be mad at me.
I just choose that I want more.
So you have to.
Because the products.
Listen.
The products are the products.
In any industry.
Dude, they're all pretty similar.
I love it.
I'm in life insurance.
Yes, me too.
It's actuarial science.
You have these conditions.
You're more apt to die.
They run the numbers.
They give you a product.
There's some variations in the product.
Don't get me wrong.
But it's real estate.
Waste management.
We picked up dumpsters.
Trash cans.
We charge about the same.
People go.
Your service is better.
What?
I picked the trash can up better.
You're telling me my service is better.
Because my truck picks it up and dumps it better.
And we drive it away.
And don't dump it on your yard.
Doesn't everybody do the exact same thing?
But I had to sell me as a person.
And me and who I am.
And the things I do.
That's why one of the things
I started doing 20 years ago.
Every morning I change my voicemail.
Every morning.
I go on not with some system.
No AI.
I change it.
My voice.
And people are like, why do you do that?
I'm like, I told every one of my clients.
If you call me.
In sales.
And these are simple things you
teach people to build their self-image.
In sales.
Come sell me.
If you call me and I
don't call you back in 24 hours.
So if you and I exchange numbers.
Okay?
Which we will.
Because I like you.
Okay?
And even if you don't
want to give it to me.
I'll get it from him.
Okay?
And then I'll call you.
If you call me ever.
Or message me.
And I don't get back to you in 24 hours.
Just call my man Cesar when we met.
And report me dead.
Because I'm dead.
And then he'll figure out who
can get the answer to you.
Hey Andrew.
Because I'm dead.
Because I return every phone
call and message within 24 hours.
And you teach people things that are simple.
Which, and by the way.
That's an anomaly nowadays.
It's an anomaly.
Work hard.
That's an anomaly.
Do what you say you're going to do.
You know what people are.
What's the number one fear?
What are clients number one fear?
In any industry.
What's their number one fear?
That you're not going to
be a man of your word.
You're going to lie to them.
Right.
I mean it's a nice way to say it.
It's very politically correct.
That you're going to freaking lie.
And they want to be a leave.
That you're not going to lie.
So I teach everybody when they start selling something.
Let me tell you something.
Because what you want from your client.
Just like when you're selling yourself.
Is you want to be brutally honest.
You want to interrogate people's reality.
Right.
So I go.
Hey man listen.
The one thing I need your
approval on before we get started is.
No matter what happens.
I won't lie to you.
But allow me to.
Are you allowing me to be honest with you?
As long as I'm being honest.
Am I willing to say
anything I can about the product.
What it means for your family.
What it'll mean if you don't get it.
Are you giving me the permission.
Your permission to be honest with me.
You're going to say yes.
And then boom.
It makes people feel better.
Because now it's like when I tell
you it costs 720 bucks a month.
For your product.
Why?
Because you had two heart attacks.
And cancer.
I love you bro.
But I'm not the one that like.
So it allows people to live in the truth.
And then deliver the information.
Without being like.
Oh my god.
What am I going to.
What if.
When I went and bid my first deal.
I told the guy we would
do a billion dollars in ten years.
We hadn't sold the policy.
A billion.
We just finished our tenth year.
We didn't do a billion.
We're just shy of 800 million.
Which was so obnoxious.
Like it's obnoxious.
But that was my goal.
And I say to him all the time.
Do you believe me?
He's like dude I didn't think you'd do 50 million.
Nobody does 50 million.
Let alone 750 million.
But it's.
But I wanted him to
know I do believe in me.
And I'm willing to do everything
that I can to get there.
And then all you got to do is show people.
Do things that you don't have to do.
That's how you build relationships.
The currency is.
Everything.
I don't have to do.
If you and I are working together.
The things I have to do.
I don't get any currency for that.
You're like well he agreed
that they're going to pay me.
They paid me.
He ate lunch with me.
Like that.
But if I start going like I'll travel to you.
I'll meet you here.
Call me at midnight.
Whatever you need.
And you start doing those things for people.
That you don't have to do.
Like when somebody holds a door for you.
I mean like.
Dude you're not supposed to slam it in my face.
Oh thanks a lot man.
You know.
But it's.
When you start accumulating those things.
That's how you sell yourself.
And dude.
It's not egotistical.
I always tell people.
If you can back it up.
It ain't bragging.
When I tell you I'll outwork everybody.
That's not bragging.
Because I will.
If.
Christian McCaffrey says.
I'm the best running back in the NFL.
And he is.
That ain't bragging dude.
He can back it up.
Yeah.
You know.
So I think.
And find the things about you that are great.
We all have them.
And.
Don't hate on yourself so much.
Everybody's like.
You need to be harder on yourself.
It's like.
Dude.
We're pretty.
People are pretty hard on themselves already.
Yeah.
I don't know if that's helping you.
You're beating yourself down.
Then you become like this martyr.
Here's why I can't do it.
Here's why I messed up.
Guy said to me the other day.
He's like.
Well.
One of my problems.
I drink too much.
And I.
I just love to drink.
I go.
Well.
I can help you.
I can stop drinking.
Yeah.
Wow.
What.
Like.
I've done it dude.
It's a pain in the ass.
You won't sleep for a while.
It will be annoying.
But you can do it.
Start taking accountability for yourself.
That's the best characteristic in sales.
Is being accountable.
Now throughout your career.
You've generated and sold.
Hundreds of millions.
Even billions of dollars.
In revenue.
Throughout your career.
But.
Like.
What has been the most amount of money.
That you've ever made in a single year.
Oh God.
I mean.
If you take.
When I've sold companies.
Obnoxious.
Tens of millions of dollars.
Immediately.
And then.
What.
When you start to make money.
It's.
Because the way I've structured them.
Is.
You know.
You get cash.
You get stock.
You get earn outs.
But.
Dude.
Like.
I never thought.
I was going to make.
Hundreds of millions of dollars.
That's obnoxious.
And it was never my goal.
Like.
It's a great question.
People understand.
Was never my goal.
And I never knew.
That you could take.
Because I never had any money.
Growing up.
I didn't have any money.
Like.
Through my 20s.
I was making enough money.
I started doing some real estate.
I started making money.
I was pouring it all back.
But I was making money.
And I saw some pretty big checks.
Like.
I did some subdivisions.
I was like.
They're going to give me.
1.6 million dollars.
For that deal.
Like.
Okay.
Done.
And I flipped houses.
Where I made a couple million dollars.
Like.
Boom.
Real fast.
Right.
Then you pay your tax.
To figure out what your deal is.
But.
When I started.
Making.
Really good money.
And.
Went to like.
Really big brokerages.
And started interviewing them.
And realized.
What I could do.
If you have.
100 million dollars.
Of what you can do with it.
And.
Here's my equities.
Here's my tax free bonds.
And here's the thing.
Here's the income.
I can spit out.
Yet my pile.
Still remains the same.
It's really.
Blown me away.
What you can do.
For your family.
And how.
Secure your income.
Can be.
As long as you're intelligent.
With it.
But.
I mean.
Honestly.
Probably more than I deserve.
You know.
The bigger deal is.
How much are we giving away.
I mean.
The.
I remember the first year.
I gave away a million dollars.
A year.
That was super awesome.
Like.
It's been really cool.
Because you look at all the people.
And I do believe.
I ain't preaching nobody.
Okay.
I don't apologize.
For having faith.
I don't believe.
I got here by accident.
But I do know.
That whatever you believe in.
The better things.
You do with your money.
The more you make.
So even.
Some of those guys.
Don't look.
Some of them.
You're talking about.
You know.
Most those guys.
Give away.
A lot of money.
Lots of money.
You go.
There's great people.
Yeah.
Or they understand the rule.
At one of your businesses.
Like.
What was the most.
That you made.
In a single year.
Like.
From.
From like.
One company.
Like.
And that's like.
In terms of like.
Revenue.
Like.
Everything.
Man.
The best.
You.
Best.
Have had.
Was last year.
And we did.
Seven hundred.
And fifty.
Two million.
In rev.
For the year.
Twenty three.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
I wouldn't lie to you.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
As a multiple.
Nine figure.
Entrepreneur.
What has been the best.
Financial advice.
That you ever received.
If there's a lesson.
About money.
That.
A mentor.
Somebody in your career.
Taught you.
That always stuck.
With you.
What's that advice.
That you pass on.
To the younger generation.
You know.
Arthur Blank is.
Very familiar.
Okay.
He.
I was in a meeting.
Probably.
God.
Maybe.
Fourteen.
Years ago.
And.
I was making.
Some money.
And trying to figure.
Some stuff out.
And.
It was funny.
Because there's only.
About ten people there.
And I paid to go.
You know.
And he asked me.
If I had any questions.
And what's weird.
About people.
Is they don't have.
No questions.
Dude.
If you.
Let.
Leave me.
In a room.
With somebody.
Doing better than me.
I will ask.
Some questions.
For like.
Literally.
Until.
They have to tell me.
Shut up.
Like that.
To be like.
Hey dude.
Like.
I'm not mad at you.
But I want to eat.
Or you're kind of.
Annoying me.
Or I got.
Take a phone call.
Because I won't stop.
Okay.
So I'm asking.
Some questions.
And he's answering.
Nobody else.
Is asking questions.
And I said.
Sir.
If you could give me.
One advice.
On why you're able.
Because at the time.
I was.
We're talking about.
Home Depot.
Why are you.
Able to launch.
Home Depot.
And it's such an amazing.
Company.
And he said.
Absolutely.
He said.
First of all.
Every business.
Opportunity.
I looked at.
I made sure.
That I always.
Fed my business.
I didn't want to starve it.
He said.
In Home Depot.
While I knew.
We were going to have.
Very small margins.
And I knew.
It would take.
While to make money.
Once we started.
Making money.
A little bit of a lot.
Been like.
More than enough.
We've had.
No problem.
So he started talking.
About that concept.
And I started listening.
He was talking.
About the patience.
In the first deals.
And the couple guys.
That were in.
That wanted their money back.
Because they didn't make.
Money right away.
And I.
And I started.
To learn patience.
From a lot of these guys.
And then.
Had a guy.
Who's a billionaire.
10, 12 times over.
And he said.
Take every business.
Opportunity.
Approach it.
Like a three legged stool.
So.
Okay.
What does that mean?
He said.
Every business.
You run.
Make sure.
Your every decision.
You make.
Any decision.
You're making.
Has to be great.
So.
A great product.
Great for the client.
Right.
Waste management.
Great service.
Good pricing.
The whole deal.
Right.
Same thing.
Real estate.
Second.
It has to be great.
For your agent.
Or your employer.
Independent contract.
Your consultant.
Okay.
So what's third?
He said.
It can't harm the company.
But that'll take patience.
Because most people.
Run their business.
Where they make every decision.
Is great for them.
Whatever scraps.
Are left.
But they don't.
Tend to be sustainable.
Because other guys.
Are doing it your way.
Now.
In the life insurance deal.
Even though we did.
That kind of rev.
Last year.
Dude.
The first three years.
I wasn't paying myself.
A lot.
And a lot of people.
Get into business.
To get rich.
Right away.
I got into business.
To get free.
And I knew.
Eventually.
I'd become wealthy.
Rich.
You could say.
I make.
You can make 400 grand.
A year.
You're rich.
I wanted to not.
Worry about money.
I wanted to build.
The things.
I want to do.
My life.
Some relatively.
Extravagant things.
And I wanted.
To not worry.
About money.
But that three legged.
Stool approach.
Is the bet.
And a little bit.
Of a lot.
Becomes more than enough.
Because.
Any business.
You're in.
Like when I launched.
My waste management.
Company.
There were huge.
Companies.
New England.
I was in New England.
My whole life.
Until four years ago.
And my buddy said.
You're never going to crack in.
They have way too big.
A presence.
Has to give me the pricing.
On all of them.
Give me the territories.
And let's analyze it.
And then we went.
We start to analyze.
It's okay.
Well let's.
Let's be clear.
We can have better pricing.
But there's certain things.
We can't do.
Like.
We can only work.
In this 20 mile.
Rate.
Like we can't go further.
Out too expensive.
For us.
Like there's things.
We can do.
We can be competitive.
And sell our clients.
On better price.
Better service.
And the guy said.
Well we won't make.
Any money for us.
I said.
I understand.
That insurance.
Is very high.
Early on.
We had to wait.
Our time.
But guess what.
When the expenses.
Started coming down.
And the income.
Continue to grow up.
And the base of clients.
Continue to grow.
And it was all.
Homeowners.
Which were credit cards.
And I wasn't chasing.
Contracts for money.
And I wasn't going.
Too far.
My pricing.
Was better.
And I was willing.
To make less.
And I had other business.
Opportunities as well.
So that's been the best.
Business lesson.
I've ever learned.
Because most people.
Get in the business.
And after about 60.
90 120 days.
Two years.
They're frustrated.
You know.
Everybody's always say.
What's the first rule business.
Stay in business.
First couple years.
But everybody says.
The grind.
Until they're in it.
And then they're like.
I can't buy that.
Four hundred thousand.
Dollar car.
And it's like.
Okay Tommy.
Welcome to the real world.
Or my mom.
Or my spouse.
My husband.
My wife.
You know.
There.
And I'm always like.
Dude.
I don't know.
I don't.
I ran my business.
I didn't take it.
Nobody.
I ran it.
I took it.
But business advice.
And people.
That were in better place.
Than me.
But personally.
Anybody around me.
That was talking.
I wasn't listening.
Nothing.
Those are my decisions.
To make.
I didn't stop.
And go.
What do you think.
I spend money on.
This is okay.
Hey mom.
I know.
I've been doing some.
Own stuff.
Was 14.
I was wondering.
What's your opinion.
On my business.
Now.
Hey.
So and so.
Uh uh.
Absolutely not.
I mean.
If people are weighing.
You down.
Dude.
You get the anchor off.
Like.
If you.
If you're a good swimmer.
If you can't swim.
And you jump in the water.
I will jump in.
To help you.
The minute.
You grab me.
And I think.
You're bringing me down.
I'm a punch you in the face.
Hard as I can.
I'm a swim back to safety.
I'm a pray for you.
I'm a call 911.
And then.
What happened.
I'm like.
I jumped in to help him.
And he started trying.
To drown me too.
I'm out.
So I will help you.
But the minute.
You're trying to drown me.
Dude.
I'm out.
And I just.
I cut it.
And I'm really.
So.
That's the best business advice.
I've gotten.
And that's the best way.
To navigate it.
But most people.
Dude.
I.
That business advice.
Is in my veins.
And when it's been hard.
Like.
You're in it for three years.
You're doing all this.
Gross revenue.
You're like.
Where is my money.
Why am I not.
Made.
But I never thought that way.
There were people.
Most.
Tons of people.
The companies.
I was running.
They're making more money.
Than me.
The first couple years.
I was a long game dude.
I was building.
Significant.
Equity.
I was funding.
My businesses.
A little bit of a lot.
Was becoming a lot.
Every decision.
I make.
Great for client.
Great for agent.
Employee.
Customer.
And then.
Couldn't harm.
Me.
There's a great saying.
In business.
That if you're not growing.
You're dying.
Now.
You've been able.
To successfully.
Grow and scale.
Multiple.
Nine-figure businesses.
What's been your secret.
To scaling.
Like.
How have you been able.
To take businesses.
From seven.
To eight.
Eventually.
Nine and ten figures.
Like.
What's the secret.
To make the most money.
On your money.
The key would be.
Never to lose.
Right.
Like.
In any given year.
Don't lose.
If I said.
Hey man.
Ten years from now.
You'd be like.
Dude.
As long as I don't lose.
In a year.
I can make seven percent.
This year.
Two percent.
Left.
But I don't have those swings.
I never went backwards.
And my.
Commitment to myself.
And the team.
Was first of all.
Everybody.
That was.
Employed.
Or working with us.
Working with me.
Had the same goal.
As me.
Any money.
They were making.
Was contingent.
On the company growing.
Anything.
It wasn't like.
Hey Tom.
You'll get this.
After a year.
You get this.
Because I know guys.
Here's our rev.
Here's our gross.
Here's our net.
We grow at this percentage.
You'll make this much more.
And I was willing to share.
A lot of it.
With the people around me.
With the understanding.
That we don't go backwards.
Like last company.
I sold.
I brought me in.
The board was there.
They're asking.
They're like.
What's your goal this year?
I'm like double.
They're like.
You're going to double.
I'm like.
Oh we'll double or die.
Like I'm doubling.
You know what I mean.
Like I'm being serious.
Like and I.
And I think for me.
I have that.
If you don't take a step.
Backwards.
It's like.
Did you play football?
I never played football.
Okay.
It's like you play linebacker.
You don't go backwards.
Like you go laterally.
But you're lateral forward.
You don't just.
These are covered.
In a run play.
You're going forward.
Like everything is.
And it's like.
As long as you don't go backwards.
You got a shot.
You can't give an inch.
And there are times.
In business.
Where I'm like.
God.
But I just kept moving.
And again.
Sometimes it was move fast.
And break things.
Like I really didn't know.
And then.
Empowering good people.
To be great.
I surrounded myself.
With people.
That started to believe.
In themselves.
And I told them.
How great they were.
Because they were.
And then I didn't steal.
All the credit.
The reason.
Most companies starve.
Is not money.
It's credit.
You run it.
And you're egotistical.
My man works there.
Now he feels like nothing.
Because you take all the credit.
Then I work there.
I get no credit.
These guys all work here.
For me.
Every ounce of credit.
If somebody.
Go to me.
Hey man.
You all did 750 million last year.
You're great.
I go.
I have great people.
Matter of fact.
Let me.
Hey.
Let you meet a couple.
They're great people.
Because you don't build second levels.
And third levels of leadership.
Because people are so full of themselves.
And if you're brilliant.
Like let's be honest.
Elon Musk can be that way.
If he wants to.
Because he's effing brilliant dude.
He's just brilliant.
He just looks at something.
And he can put you on a different planet.
I can't.
Most of us can't.
And I recognize that about myself.
So for me.
I'm always trying to build additional leaders.
That are bought into the plan.
Where we're doing it together.
When people say.
You know.
I.
It's always we.
You have a great company.
No.
We have a great company.
When you launched it.
When we launched it.
Y'all.
You killed it Sean.
No.
We killed it.
We're in this together.
Hey.
And by the way.
What that means too is.
If you're getting the credit.
When it's going well.
You're going to take the.
You're going to take the blame.
It's going.
Like.
That's part of your business.
If you're running an agency.
With 200 people.
And I take the credit.
When it's going good.
That means I better take the blame.
When it goes bad.
And I'm not going to take the blame.
I'm not going to take the credit.
Nor am I going to take the blame.
And it's a very fair deal.
And also interrogate reality with people.
I interrogate your reality.
If you're doing well.
I'm going to tell you you're doing well.
If you're not doing well.
I'm going to be honest with you about it.
I want you to be honest with me.
If I'm not doing well.
Like we're going to be a bunch of grown-ups.
We're going to talk about it.
Like it's a locker room.
And we all want to win.
Because right now.
It's like.
If you talk to guys.
That.
We have a bunch of guys that work with me.
It's a pre-season game.
And every one of them is like.
Dude.
Just the older dudes letting us know.
Like this.
Like this is real now.
This is how we feed our families.
Like don't F it up.
Like no.
Now there's NIL with college.
I get it.
But back in the day.
There was no money.
And now all of a sudden.
It's.
This is an adult game.
If you work at my company.
I'm responsible for what you're doing.
Just like you are with me.
And it's not a game.
And what happens to most people.
Is they get in the business with people they know.
People they like.
Right.
Like you all work together.
You look like you like each other.
You got your brother's ball.
You have your girlfriend's football.
You got your girlfriend's football.
You guys are doing great.
So.
Familiarity always breeds contempt.
I find a way to keep people.
I love them.
I respect them.
I want to be.
But it's business first.
I started answering the phone all the time.
What's up.
Because my friends at work.
Maybe would call me.
Why?
They want to talk.
And I'd be like.
Hey.
And I start talking.
Like what am I doing.
So finally I was like.
What's up.
And they started pushing back.
Like oh man.
Well nice to talk to you too.
I'm like dude.
What's up.
I'm busy.
I'm not mad at you.
grow we'll hang out and have a lot of fun
in the future right now what's up means what's mother
effing up yeah makes sense yeah that's i love
that another another thing i wanted to ask you
about right i love the quote it says i'd much
rather have a slice of the pie or a slice of
the watermelon than 100 of the grape and a lot
of people they want to be that solopreneur wear all
the hats themselves how important was it for you
as a business owner to learn how to delegate and
bring in the right people dude probably the biggest mistake
i made early on was trying to be all things
and it wasn't like i just i was doing pretty good
and i figure hell i got a handle on this i'll never
forget when i had a company first i talked about
looking at selling and god they called me up and
they said well can you have all your c-level
executives there first of all i didn't know what
c-level executives meant and when i don't know
something i ask the dumbest people in the world
are people that somebody says something and they go it
would be dumb for me to ask right i don't
know what that means no it's dumb for you not
to ask like no but that's weird right be transparent
so i was like what does that
mean and she was super nice she
was super nice and i was like what does that
mean and she was super nice she was super nice
she was i guess the admin to the ceo
she goes well all of you c-level executives i'm like
ma'am i'm not trying to be rude i don't know what
you mean she's like ceo cfo co cto and i'm like oh
okay got it it'll just be me and i
never forget when i started meeting with people like dude
you're wearing way too many hats like like you
can't wear this it's not about the work you can't
possibly be wearing this man you're not even skilled
enough you might be good in the ceo role
but not the cfo
role or the ceo and i sure as hell was
not qualified to be in technology role so i learned
to delegate really fast because i'm a good learn
i'm a good student like once i realized damn i
suck at that i got to fix it so once
that happened to me after a couple companies i started me
looking inside going okay okay he's good with tech
let me bring him on from the outside cool
you're my cto got it he's really good if i'm okay
he's done back all right you're my cfo so i started
surrounding my it didn't mean i needed to pay
them all astronomical amount of money it was just
getting them to delegate things because that freed
me up to do what i'm good at
and i think that's what i learned is when
you're bogged down with all these things you can't
possibly be great at all you know i mean
i'm really really good at getting people to sell
and talking to them and motivating them
and inspiring them and handling crisis like all
those things but dude for me to sit down look
at spreadsheets and pretend i'm a cfo not my thing
i'll do it don't love it but i'd rather have an
objective guy go hey we talk you know once a week
he's like here's what you got here's where we're going
it's made my life so much easier so now i
can be like you're a great football player you're
not gonna go play tennis you're like dude what am
i doing over here like i'm great at this so
that please don't try to wear too many hats and there's
a lot and i was willing to spend the money
it wasn't like i was afraid to spend the money
i just had never built anything like that so i was
like do i really need these people and i have my
vision and what i learned was my vision was still
my vision what this guy was doing was he was
handling the numbers this guy was bringing me tech
that helped me with my vision because i believed in
my business because we're growing like crazy so i
don't want to mess with my vision so it's like
i can just delegate to them and they want to
help build it and by the way sometimes they have ideas
about the vision i used to be so stupid that
i would say the new idea department is closed don't
bring me any ideas like straight up across the
board now when you're in crisis mode that's okay
like if you and i are launching a business we've
been in it for six weeks we're just trying to stay
afloat i really don't need we don't need new ideas
half the day we need to go sell something make
something change so it's really it's really about
two hours i think whatever we denkt about
so he i think every no matter what will be
correct
if youár
and
of people a lot of good ideas and in corp
and having these teams now where now it used to be
staff meeting was me everything was me and
selling companies and seeing the way their structure when
they get massive and that's part of why i did some
of the deals it was kind of like i've taken this
as far as i can take it but weirdly
enough in real estate waste management i probably could have
brought the infrastructure in and continue to scale the
hell out of it and that's okay i'm glad
i did but in life engineers i learned i
partnered with a company that had all that infrastructure
and they just i mean we grew oh my
god 700 a couple years because they had the infrastructure
you know and had all those executives so most
people try to try to wear all those hats and
nobody can wear them all yeah now have you ever
been broke before oh god yeah dude i was um
so when i graduated college i used to party a lot
um i went to the police academy i didn't we want
to be a cop my buddy mike took the exam
and i was like dude i've been arrested like eight times
for fighting dudes and drinking
and drugs or no way and they hired me which
is mind-boggling and then uh so i was making no
money and then i left there or they were like dude
this is gonna be a bad idea i actually tackled the
guy and he was not the guy that i was
supposed to be tackling it was a victim running from the
perpetrator which is not my fault because he
shouldn't have been running like a grown man
but i tackled them and they're like dude we're
probably gonna fire you and they did and then i
took a job working with abusing like the children dude
i was grinding man i was in real estate a
couple young kids um i filed bankruptcy when i was young
i got i got a real estate i was like 18 19.
bought a house and didn't really know what i was
doing i filed bankruptcy um it my son i remember
he had um he needed like special formula and it
was hard i mean it was it was just even trying
to be able to pay for that dude i was broke and
i was raised with absolutely no money like none
my mentorship early on was coaches of kids in
the towns around me that did better than me
because their dads a lot of them were athletes
they wanted to coach they wanted me to play because
i was pretty good so like they wanted me to help
their kid win and then i could ask him a bunch
of advice i was broke as hell we live in a one-bedroom
apartment me and my mom and my dad were doing it
all the time and he was like i'm gonna go to the
gym i'm gonna northwest because you need to get
right i can't let my kid be safe and and
then there were a couple other kids that could
that they could do anything but i knew i just
didn't move at all they from this little suburb
was just throw away all they had that the product
right when they they basically
was kind of like a waste
생 a daughter you questioned him back and was like
oh yeah wait man hey i'm not scared i got
my hands clean up my shoes i ain't fucking acting like
a waiter in bed like come on my god dude to it
Yeah, man, I spent a good amount of my life.
And I was broke from the day I
was born until I left my mom's apartment.
I was still broke for the
next probably four or five years.
And then I got tired of it, dude.
And I just put enough work
in where things started to happen.
Yeah, so let me ask you this because you hear
the saying, the rich get richer, the poor get poorer.
For somebody who may be stuck
in that cycle of poverty right now,
what is an actionable step that somebody
could take to really break out of that?
Like you said, you've been at rock bottom before.
For somebody there right now, what's an actionable step
somebody could take to escape the cycle of poverty?
Well, first of all, dude, the poor, that's bullshit.
You know what I mean?
And that's what people want you to believe.
First of all, if you're not where you want to be,
don't talk to anybody that ain't where you want to be.
And the reality is capitalism works because the
majority of people think they can't make any money.
That's why it works.
Fear sells, good and bad.
It sells.
So first of all, don't be afraid, right?
Because that's where most – and if you
get to be around people that make money,
the greatest gift I got was to
get around people that are making money.
You know what I found out about them?
They're not that smart.
They're not.
Like I don't care.
You –
I see a lot of people I meet them to.
You meet them.
You interview them.
And it's like, oh, I wouldn't want him
on my team if it was an academic event.
He ain't that smart.
But guess what?
He's successful.
So if it's not intellectual capacity and it
doesn't matter who your mom or dad was,
now at some point in time in
your family, you got to break the mold.
My desire, honestly, dude, was I wanted to be
somebody in my family that was like, you know what?
We don't have to live this way.
We do not have – if we don't
want it, we don't have to live this way.
I'm tired of everybody telling us
that we have to stay broke.
Be careful.
If it was so easy, everybody would do it.
It's too good to be true.
People tell me all the time, there's
no way people make that kind of money.
That's complete bullshit.
It's too good to be true.
And I just didn't listen to anybody.
So it's a myth.
If you find – here's what I know.
The greatest equalizer is sales because anybody can do it.
Find a product that you love
and work your ass off selling it.
Get really good at selling it and then
find other people you can teach to sell it.
And then when you can find those people and
teach them and teach other people to recruit people
and sell it, you're going to be a great person.
I don't care what the product is.
I don't care if it's a new product.
You just start an agency.
You start an organization.
You start a business.
But it's the greatest equalizer.
And that's what I found.
What can I do?
Well, I don't have a lot of money growing up.
Okay, so I can't invest in business.
I don't have any money.
Man, I don't have a lot of business acumen.
I really don't know a lot of people either.
So wait a minute.
When I started watching sales, I kept hearing people say,
sales is the highest paid occupation in America.
I've been hearing that for 30 years.
I'm like, okay, so why don't I participate
in the highest paid occupation and then fund businesses?
And then I was like, wait a minute.
In the highest paid occupation, I can
sell and build a business in that.
Because you know what?
While sales is not a skill set,
most people don't want to work hard.
So I found the people that had distribution
or the people that were already really wealthy,
they needed me.
They needed me to sell.
They weren't going to go sell.
They weren't going to grind.
They couldn't teach people to sell.
And they couldn't connect with a lot
of people like me, blue collar people,
that they wanted to sell their products.
So they needed me.
And I also understood that
people were going to use you.
And I'm cool with that.
Like, that sounds weird to people.
People are like, man, I'm glad
he was your mentor growing up.
I'm like, dude, he's my mentor because his kid sucked.
And he wanted me on his travel team.
Oh, that's really nice that he bought your, you
know, paid for you to travel to Maine to play.
I'm like, he did it because I'm good.
I hit third.
I pitch every game.
I'm not trying to be an
app, but like he was using me.
And I was perfectly fine with that.
My football coach did it.
I was totally good with it.
And the minute I was done
playing for them, those mentorship things stopped.
I was fine with that.
I wasn't like all in my feelings, man.
I was using them too.
I will go play hard.
I will be more respectful.
I won't cuss you out during
the game because I want your knowledge.
I don't need you to help me.
Like, I ain't going to play professional baseball 15 years.
I ain't going to play in the NFL.
I'm slow as shit.
I was slow then.
I'm slower now.
I ain't playing in the NFL.
But I knew that about me.
But I'm like, I'm pretty good at this level.
I can play in college.
Life is good.
And I think along your journey,
it's finding people because guess what?
Let's say you're a really good salesperson.
You can connect with the highest people at the company.
You can get their mentorship.
You can ask questions because you have a value add.
And they're going to use
you and let them do it.
And it's okay.
And they're not your best friends.
I have people that are really friendly with me.
And I'm their number one distributor.
And then I go do
something else or work with them.
And all of a sudden, like, and people are
like, I thought you were really close with him.
And I'm like, dude, what are you, five years old?
Like, we're not in the Boy Scouts together.
He runs a massive company.
He's worth a bunch of money.
And we talk.
And now that I'm doing business over here, he's good.
But along the way, I'm not a boy scout.
I'm not a boy scout.
And along the way, you need to accumulate those relationships
and get the most out of them while you have them.
But this idea that you can't make money because of where you're
born or who your family was or what you look like, that's bullshit.
And if you're perpetuating that, that's your weakness.
And you should believe in yourself because
also, I wanted to show my mom.
I wanted my mom because everybody around me told
me I wanted to show my mom to this day.
Can you understand that?
When I told my mom I was leaving my job as a social
worker, she, like, literally was like, well, I thought you would be sober forever.
I'm like.
I am sober.
She's like, are you sure you're okay?
Nobody leaves a state job.
I'm like, yeah, I want to go make.
I just would be really careful out there
because it's not what you think it is.
I'm like.
And I'm not mad at her, but
I was like, I'm not listening to her.
Why am I taking advice from her?
And you could take one hand and count the amount of people
in your life that will pull for you if it doesn't benefit them.
It's not many.
You don't need both hands.
You probably don't need all five fingers.
And it's okay as long as
you know that going into it.
People will cheer and pull for you when you're.
Doing things that benefit them.
And then when you're not, they're probably not going to.
But what if you cheer enough for you?
What if you don't?
What if you find one or two or three people?
That's enough, dude.
That's a quorum.
Now you can go to work.
So don't buy into that, dude.
I think that's changing in America.
Actually, I think if you look over the next 20, 30, 40, 50
years and see the people where they are from an income level now.
Because, you know, I was
with Damon John doing a podcast.
And he says the first generation creates it.
It's a good thing.
Second generation enjoys it.
Third generation destroys it.
And we're on a lot of this third.
Like where I live, there's a lot
of this third generation taking these houses over.
They can't keep them.
They can't afford taxes.
There's no mortgage on them.
But the taxes where I
live on the water are obnoxious.
And they just can't afford it.
And it's like they're looking
around like, what do I do?
And there's a lot of
that first generation like I was.
I don't know your whole situation.
But everybody like there's a lot of those folks
are going like, I'm going to get my piece.
Now of the American dream.
And it's the greatest country as
far as opportunity goes in the world.
Dude, anybody says that's not true is a liar.
Right.
When it comes to the way that people look at money, what would you say is the number one thing
that separates the middle class from those who are able to build that long term generation of wealth like yourself?
Right.
Like what is it in your opinion when you look
at people and how they perceive and look at money?
What is it that really separates middle class from wealthy?
It's learned behavior.
Right.
Like so.
So the way I was raised, I think a lot
of people are raised is you get a good job.
It's always like get a good job.
And then you put.
Put the money away.
Right.
You put in a 401k.
Like I was 18.
They want to.
They want to put money in a 401k at 18.
I said, so I can't touch that money
until I'm 59 and a half without penalty.
I'm 18 years of age.
This is 18.
I'm like, you're telling me that you want me to
give you money that you all get to make money on.
And then if the next 41 and a half years,
I want to use it to create more wealth for me.
You're going to smoke me and
take a huge percentage of it.
Like, but people do it because we just were cheap.
We like this.
Learn behavior.
Get a good job.
Put money in your 401k.
Do this over here.
Debt's bad.
Debt's not bad.
But here, one more person.
And again, it always makes me laugh.
These guys will go online, tell you debt's bad, and then charge you to be
in a course to continue to tell you debt's bad and help you financially plan.
Get a piece of paper and here's your budget.
Spend this much money.
They scare you into greatest thing
ever happened to me in business.
Going bankrupt.
Greatest thing.
The greatest thing ever taught me is the best lesson.
I didn't have a lot to discharge.
Best lesson I ever learned.
I.
It hurt.
It made me focus.
I paid attention.
And immediately what I thought about was I got to
get back to building my credit so I can borrow money.
And a year and a half later, I went to
a local bank, got a million dollar line of credit.
Boom.
Million dollars.
Build a subdivision.
Then I was borrowing two, three, five, ten.
I was borrowing money at interest rates of
14, 15 percent in the 80s and 90s.
Okay.
Late 80s, 90s.
Right.
And I was borrowing hard money.
You know what hard money is?
Okay.
So hard money is an old school saying.
You still hear people say it now.
But it's like you couldn't go to a traditional bank.
Okay.
You want to do a project.
You're a real estate investor.
And you're like, man, I can't find the bank.
It's not going to give me the money.
I go, hey, bro, I'll do it.
I'll give you $200,000.
I'll charge you 12 percent
interest, which is obnoxious, right?
Then you'll pay me points.
You know how points work?
You can credit card points.
Okay.
So it's like it's a percent every way.
So I'm like, okay, you're going to
pay me 10 points every six months.
By the time you pay me
back, I made a boatload of money.
And you got.
You got.
But.
But I borrowed hard money all the time.
Because I knew I could.
I knew I could.
People that understand money know the value of what
they can do to make money with the money.
And people that are broke mindset think that they're
just supposed to make enough money to live on,
get a vacation once a
year, and then die one day.
And their headstone says, there lies Tom, good bill payer.
There's Tom, good bill payer.
Tom did everything he was supposed to do.
He worked his job, 401K.
Then what's the number one fear of seniors nowadays?
Outliving their money, they say.
I was reading a study the other day.
They're terrified to outlive.
Think about that.
You're scared to be in good health.
Because people are in better health nowadays.
Like somebody said to me, why are
you so focused on being in good health?
I'm like, dude, I make money.
Like, I want to live as long as I can.
I'm not terrified that I can't pay my bills.
That's what scared me when I got into life insurance.
Started seeing all these people that were in their
60s and 70s and 80s, and they're broke as hell.
And I'm like, dude.
And they were like, had jobs.
They did what everybody told them to do.
They got a good job.
They put the kids through school.
They had a bunch of debt.
They had a credit card.
They had, I mean, they never.
Understood the power of leveraging money.
Me, I was never afraid of that.
I was dying to get it.
I was dying to take my
money and make money with it.
You know, when I've done some of these deals.
People are like, there's ways you can like take this,
and then you get an LOA, and you pay your taxes.
But you didn't really.
And then it's their money.
And then you're like, okay, well, they charged me 3%.
But I'm making 8.
And it's their money.
And it wasn't out of my account.
And like, I borrowed the money.
Debt is really good.
I'll tell everybody right now.
Everybody listen.
You want to lend me money?
You want to lend me money under 4%?
I'll take it.
Don't matter to me at all.
Just call me up.
I'll take it right now.
A million, two, five, 20, 150.
Because I can, with my eyes closed, make a hell
of a lot more money with the money than that.
And that's the thing that people that
are raised with a broke mindset don't understand.
They're terrified of debt.
And I'm running to it.
When I did that subdivision.
When I continue to do that.
When I borrowed those.
When I borrowed the money.
And, you know, it's sad because what sells that?
Fear.
It's just fear.
Like, people are like, what about politics?
Dude, who cares?
You got to take care of you.
Something's going to happen.
You become proactive, not reactive in your business.
But it doesn't matter unless you let it consume you.
And also, I'll be honest.
The people I grew up with, they're very problem focused.
And the successful people I know are solution focused.
They love problems.
They love it.
Like, growing up, it's always on TV.
Morpovich, Jerry Springer.
Why?
Because it's somebody's bullshit drama.
And we love drama.
Dude, people making money that are wealthy in
time and money, they don't have time for it.
They don't, like, watch that.
They don't think it's funny.
They don't think it's cool.
And they just keep it moving.
And they kind of hope that everybody else is
watching it because that's what's going to work for them.
And never want more.
Yeah.
I love that.
What was the lowest point in
your career as a business owner?
Oh, man.
There's a lot of them.
The lowest point was probably the last.
And it's grown to an unbelievable company.
Yeah.
But we were in business, like, seven months.
And I had left another company.
And that guy had sued me.
Right?
And it was costing a lot of money.
But I was working.
I was paying it.
Right?
And then the court had entered this order that
said we couldn't do what we were doing anymore.
Basically, a restraining order.
Just like you do in, like, criminal court.
Like, a civil court temporary restraining order.
My attorney called me.
I was doing a meeting in Florida at the time.
Destin.
And my attorney called me,
like, seven times in a row.
He's not usually, like, a
big 911 panic button pushing guy.
So, I went outside.
He said, what's up?
I called him.
And he's like, hey, man, it's over.
And I'm like, what do you mean?
He's like, dude, it's over.
Like, court entered an order.
You can't do it anymore.
And I was like.
And it felt like somebody literally punched me.
You ever been punched in the stomach?
That's exactly what it felt like.
Like, the wind was knocked out of me.
And I literally didn't know what was happening.
Like, I got to go.
And immediately, it wasn't.
Like, I was going to be fine financially either way.
But I'm like, dude, I have
all these people that have joined me.
I got, like, 1,400 people now that are relying on me,
both employees and agents, to make we can't be out of business.
And I never.
I went back.
I did the meeting.
Because they were waiting inside for me.
It was probably 100 people.
Go back in.
Suck it up.
Bite my lip.
Try not to want to punch the wall or cry.
Finish the meeting.
And then all of a sudden, it
was like, just like, wait a minute.
I called him.
I was like, hey, dude, if
I violate the order, what happens?
He's like, we go to court.
I'm like, all right, let's just keep moving.
I'll violate the restraining order.
And I'll see him in court.
He's like, OK, I wouldn't suggest it.
I'm like, well, I'm not asking your suggestion.
You're an attorney.
Your advice would be do nothing, obviously.
I'm going to go to court.
Let's fight it.
I don't believe that's valid anyway.
Dude, I mean, I don't stop doing anything.
They immediately file and say
I violated it, which I did.
Go to this big federal court in Greensboro.
And they're like, well, you know,
you might not be able to.
They might arrest you.
And I was like, what, in federal prison?
That'd be like going to day camp.
Four days, I'd be less stressed than anything.
Like, I'm all good.
But we went in.
The judge went through everything.
And he was like, yeah, I don't even know why.
And they threw it all out.
And we moved on.
And you can keep doing what you're doing.
But it was because I really felt.
And I was like, dude, these people are all
going to like, I can't let them all down.
You know, like they came over to
work with me from all these industries.
And some were already in life insurance.
And how do I let them down?
But the lesson I learned from
that was don't take it personally.
Because weirdly enough, the dude that sued me, that
did everything he could to put me out of business,
I talked to that dude.
I call him today.
He called me.
Like, I wasn't happy with what happened.
But it's not personal, dude.
This is business.
Do I like a lot of it?
No.
But I done it the way it did?
But you know what?
It's just business.
But that was.
That was a really low point.
I've been broke before.
But that was the first time in my life
that I'm like, I let all these people down.
Because being broke on my own,
bankruptcy, whatever else, that was on me.
But all these other people, that was a low point.
And that eight days from
that day to court was painful.
Right.
Let me ask you this.
Because failure is something
that's inevitable in entrepreneurship.
A lot of people, they'll fail at
one thing and they immediately want to quit.
Right?
For somebody who may be going through
that storm in their business right now,
what advice would you give to them?
You know, when you were ever facing challenges,
setbacks, and even today, like,
what is your advice to somebody who may be
going through that storm right now in their business?
Well, first of all, perspective.
You know, I had a guy one day say,
if your biggest issue is financial, get down
on your hands and knees and thank God.
And that's really powerful.
Right?
Or another buddy of mine is much harsher.
He said, you know, 155,000
people didn't wake up this morning,
so have some respect for yourself.
So perspective first.
Like, and also, dude, at the end of the day,
like, we think it's such a big deal.
Right?
When something happens.
Like, we think it's.
It's so big.
Dude, not about 24 hours
ain't a big deal at all.
So the answer is, you can
only control what you can control.
So right now, you're in chaos.
And it sucks.
You can't believe it.
Sit down.
Get your phone.
Write it out.
What are the things that you can control?
Out of the situations happening, these are 10 things.
Which one?
If none of them you can
control, you're along for a ride.
If you can't control them, then you got to.
But there probably are things you can control.
But you can't control all of them.
Man, I didn't know that
customer was going to file that.
I didn't know that they
were going to cancel that order.
Man, I didn't know.
Like, I put out 200 grand in my marketing.
Nobody showed up.
Okay.
Dude, I was traveling all over the country.
Nobody showed up to meetings.
That's how you built it.
When you started this, how many people were watching?
Not many.
Did you think it'd be as big as it is?
Got 3 million now.
No, I know how big you are.
You're massive.
Did you think it would be this big?
Always had that vision.
You hoped it would be this big or
did you think it would be that big?
I never thought it would get to this point.
Okay.
Because this is obnoxious.
I mean, 3 million people.
How many people live in America?
3 billion or.
Hundreds of millions.
360 million, something like that, yeah.
Dude, I mean.
I mean, you get to 36 million.
I mean, like, think about the percentage
of the population that has seen you.
Right.
The population in a, like, obviously worldwide, but
look at the amount of people that have
seen you.
But at the end of the day, all
you did was kept doing what you could control.
And again, there were times that it sucked.
There were times I was on,
you ever heard of Evan Carmichael?
Yes.
Okay.
Evan's a great guy.
Evan was reading me his YouTube followers
that I had him on my podcast.
Which, by the way, you have
to get on my podcast now.
Yeah.
Because you're a stud.
So I want you to get on.
So you're saying yes, like you're going
to do it, or are you debating?
Okay, good, because I need you on that.
Okay, so Evan was reading me the YouTube followers.
And it's just like, I'm like, what'd you do?
He goes, just kept doing what
I thought I needed to do.
First of all, it's never as
bad as you think it is.
It's never as bad as you think it is.
It's just not.
You start getting in your own
head and think it's worse than this.
Find somebody you can trust.
Like, if I'm going through something,
I know who I can call.
If you're going through something, you
should have somebody you can call.
Right?
Boom.
I'm wondering what I can do.
Like, you should have that.
Talk to anybody you know.
If you don't know anybody, buckle down.
Find these things you can control.
And don't think about any of the rest of it.
And all of a sudden, we start
thinking about, wonder what he's going to say.
I wonder what she's going to say.
Dude, who gives a shit what they say?
The greatest gift of public speaking is getting up
in front of people and not caring what they think.
I like you a lot.
Like y'all.
You're all really good people.
I want to do right by you, 100%.
But I'm not going to sit around and
think about, like, you're 3 million people to watch.
I hope that I provide some value.
Absolutely.
But guess what?
What do you want me to do?
Like, I can only do the best I can do.
And somebody's going to go, I
don't like it for that reason.
Okay, cool.
Thanks.
But as long as you're resilient to that, so
focus on what you can control, get good mentorship.
Don't worry about everything else flying around you.
Everybody's got an opinion.
And it's not near as
bad as you think it is.
Because we think it's so bad.
And I was reading this the other day.
Not that I'm a huge
either way Drake fan or not.
But he went through something.
And he was like, my mom said, like, you're Drake.
In 72 hours, nobody cares.
Well, if in 72 hours, nobody cares for Drake,
then about 7.2 seconds, nobody cares if it involves me.
You know, so who cares?
Like, let's just keep it moving.
And by the way, that
means you're on the right path.
I've been kicked in the stomach
thousands of times in my business.
Thousands.
I was in the waste management business rolling.
Like, we were rolling.
And then all of a sudden, my guy calls me.
He's like, hey, dude, the incinerator burnt to the ground.
How's the incinerator burnt?
Like, that's where we brought our trash.
I was like, well, bring it to another incinerator.
He goes, that's the only one in Connecticut.
I go, where do we dump it?
He's like, the only other place to
dump it, all the guys own them.
So our competition owns all the landfills.
I was like, well, that sucks.
Start trying to negotiate that.
Dude, I had nowhere to dump trash
for, like, a week and a half.
Like, that ain't fun.
Pick it up.
Okay, I'll leave it in the dumpster on the truck.
And at some point in time, like, I'll get
in trouble if I don't get rid of it.
But you know what?
Then it was like, I just kept taking a step.
I go, what can I control?
All right, you know, I can negotiate with this guy.
This guy won't negotiate with me.
Let me negotiate.
I don't want to do that.
But you know what?
And maybe I'll do it for that amount.
Man, I'll be losing money, but maybe I
can negotiate something in 120 days with him.
And then I had to find,
then I was like, wait a minute.
Who do I know that knows one of them?
Then I took a step back.
What can I control?
Oh, my buddy over here knows this dude's attorney.
Let me call him and triangulate it.
So I started becoming very solution-focused.
When it's going bad and you become
solution-focused, dude, you're hard to deal with.
If you will continue to work,
not complain, be solution-focused in that perspective,
as long as you're in industry as an employer,
and you're not going to be a
lawyer, you're not going to be a lawyer.
You're not going to be a lawyer.
You're going to kick ass.
Love it.
How old are you now?
And how old were you when you became a millionaire?
First year that I drew and made a million
dollars in a year, I think I was 41.
Yeah.
Let me ask you this.
I'm going to end with this one.
A young 20-year-old kid watching this right now,
aspiring to become a multimillionaire like yourself, right?
They want to own a private
jet one day just like you.
What advice would you give to them?
Give them the blueprint of
what it really takes to create,
build that long-term generational wealth like you.
If you could leave them with a couple last
words, a couple last sound bites on what it really,
really takes.
How can somebody own a private jet in today's world?
Well, first of all, owning a private jet is expensive.
You know, if you're like, I'm going to buy it.
Dude, buying ain't the problem.
Maintaining it is the problem.
You know what I mean?
Sitting around costs you $150,000 a month, minimally.
Blueprint, though, right, is at any
age, but let's take a 20-year-old, right?
It's understanding what's really possible
and surrounding yourself with good people.
I found a really good attorney.
So that story I told you, also the
end result is I had a really good attorney.
I found a really good accountant.
Early on.
Like, even though there were
probably more than I could afford,
but I found a really
good attorney, a really good accountant.
And then once I started making money, I
found a, like, I can manage my money,
but, dude, I can't spend all
day long and do what they do.
I can't research funds and this
over here and the IPO market.
I can't do that all day long.
So I find people that can, right?
So connect yourself with good people early.
Ingratiate yourself to them.
How do you do that?
Ask good questions.
A lot of people want to mentor people.
They do.
They're just never asked.
And the reason that most people
don't want to mentor, it's like you.
How many people have asked you about what you do?
They're not listening.
You start answering.
They talk over you.
They're not really going to do it.
They're like, how did you get to 3 million?
You start talking like, yeah, I know.
Like, I did it.
You're like, right?
You're kind of like disheartened.
You're like, I'm just trying to help you.
I got a few minutes to talk to you.
Can you shut up while I give you the answer?
But they can't do it.
And then you don't want to mentor.
You're like, dude, this is a waste of my time.
And it's actually a waste of his time, too.
And I don't want to waste our time, right?
So you find people that are willing to mentor you.
And also do capital.
I found my capital in local banks.
I found my capital in
people that would invest in me.
I do it now.
I have people that now I'm doing the other.
Now they're like, will you join us?
Be on the board.
Help us with this fund.
And we're going to acquire businesses in this industry.
OK, cool.
Because I've done it.
And I can manage it.
And I have a unique ability to
talk to both the sales and the leadership.
The distribution.
And be somebody that can continue to talk to everybody.
While I was at Real Estate, I was in a
meeting when I got that million dollar line of credit.
And the president of the bank,
who was like 80 years old,
pulled me aside afterwards and said,
I'm going to give you the money.
But I'm going to tell you what
your greatest skill set is right now.
And he did that because
I was always asking him questions.
He never even answered me.
I was always nice.
He answered every once in a while.
He pulled me aside because I
was so willing to be mentored.
And he said, you have a
unique ability to talk to everybody.
You can go in this meeting and talk to us.
You can go to the job site,
get in the garage, talk to the sheetrockers.
You can go up on a roof and tell
the roofers to be like, you can talk to everybody.
You have this ability to communicate with everybody.
Learn to be flexible and
learn to have great communicative ability.
How do you do it?
Watch other people that are good at it.
I learned by watching people that were great at it.
My old mentor growing up was really good at it.
He played professional baseball 12 years.
He was super smart.
He built a massive real estate company.
But he could, I mean, property management,
he'd get in the meeting and explain why.
And his word and his favorite word was
F this, F that, F this, F that,
which I was comfortable with
because that's how I was raised.
So I'm like, I'm all in.
But he could talk to everybody.
Then he could go walk and
talk to anybody in front of anybody,
anything eloquently, professionally.
So learn to be all things
to all people, if you will,
until you find out where you actually
need to live and make your money.
And you develop those relationships growing up.
And you've found a niche.
People your age want to know shit.
And you're getting it for them.
And you have the courage to go ask people.
First time you went up to
somebody randomly and asked them a question,
was it uncomfortable?
Yes.
Yes, of course.
And if you were like, no, it's not.
It may lie.
Of course it was.
But you did it anyway.
Why'd you do it?
I saw the potential there.
Correct.
To create something great.
And also maybe other people
didn't have the courage you did.
Maybe they wouldn't ask.
Maybe you're asking questions of people
that everybody wants the answers to
and they're too afraid to ask.
They walk out in places
and see people with nice cars.
I've never had one person.
I had one guy the other day.
I hired him.
A month ago.
Stop me in the road.
Come down to me.
I was like, so I do what I do.
I reach for my gun.
Because I'm like, this is about
to get ugly for this fool.
So I'm a really good shot.
You know what I mean?
So I just grab my gun.
I make sure there's a bolt in the chamber.
And I just roll the window down.
And I'm just got my gun here
waiting to see if he does something stupid.
Pop, pop.
And I'm going to go on my way.
And he stopped.
I said, dude, what are you doing?
And he's like, sorry.
Sorry.
I go, what are you standing
in the middle of the road for?
He's like, how did you get this car?
I said, I bought it.
He said, I've always wanted a Ferrari.
I said, congratulations.
I said, you know you can get run over
by stopping people in the middle of the road, right?
He goes, yeah, I'm sorry.
I said, how old are you?
He said, 18 years of age.
I go, what are you doing down here?
He goes, I'm a student at FAU.
And I take care of
some of the boats down here.
I clean them.
I said, how can I help you?
He goes, how did you buy the car?
I said, cash.
I said, ask better questions and I'll answer them.
He goes, what did you do to make the money?
I said, become great at freaking sales.
Do you want to work with me?
He's like, yes.
And I was like, good.
Get your Instagram.
Boom.
Hired him, got him in class.
He's selling life insurance.
But most people won't.
But I've never had anybody else.
I mean, dude, please don't stand in
the road and get in front of everybody.
Because that was a little bit crazy, right?
But it's getting people to understand that dynamic, right?
Is you have that courage.
Now you have an obligation
to stand up for other people.
Because they don't have that courage.
Right?
And if you're young enough and you're willing
to, because what you just said is the key.
Every time it's uncomfortable, you're on to something.
Every time it's uncomfortable, accept it.
You're growing.
Because like, here's you.
Here's your client.
Here's you.
Here's your customer.
Here's your lender.
And you have to get uncomfortable
to get them in the middle too.
You can't just live in comfortableness.
If you're willing to get crazy uncomfortable at your
age, you're willing to surround yourself with good people.
You're willing to be teachable.
And don't be egotistical.
Nobody likes it.
Do very well.
Be humble.
Breathe life into people.
Dude, you'll make as much money as you want.
And that's a fact.
That was phenomenal.
Sean.
That was good?
That was one of the best interviews I've ever done.
I promise you.
You're great, dude.
Guys, that's a wrap on today's video.
Be sure to leave a like
and subscribe for amazing content coming soon.
We're on a way to bring you guys some of
the best advice from some of the most successful business owners
in the world.
We'll see you next time.
Bye.
...the entire world.
So stay tuned for that.
Sean, where can everybody find you out?
Anywhere, man.
Instagram.
My name is Sean, S-H-A-W-N.
Mike is my last name, but it's M-E-A-I-K-E.
My YouTube channel is that.
Closing Congress, a podcast that you're going to be on.
And you're going to kill it.
So Instagram, YouTube, follow, like, share, please.
Because this guy is an absolute stud, man.
It's an honor to talk to you, bro.
A lot of people do this,
but a lot of them aren't good.
Yeah.
And you're really good, man.
Appreciate you.
Appreciate you, dude.
And guys, be sure to click here to
watch our full video going all over Dallas,
asking multimillionaires how they became wealthy
and how you can start your
path to becoming financially free in 2024.